<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cyber Security on UKmac.net - Apple news, tech views</title><link>https://ukmac.net/categories/cyber-security/</link><description>Recent content in Cyber Security on UKmac.net - Apple news, tech views</description><generator>Hugo - gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ukmac.net/categories/cyber-security/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Online Safety Bill Climb Down</title><link>https://ukmac.net/p/online-safety-bill-climb-down/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ukmac.net/p/online-safety-bill-climb-down/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://ukmac.net/p/online-safety-bill-climb-down/osb.png" alt="Featured image of post Online Safety Bill Climb Down" />&lt;p>Yesterday the &lt;a class="link" href="https://bills.parliament.uk/bills/3137" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Online Safety Bill&lt;/a> was taken through the House of Lords for the final time. On this reading the contentious requirement for companies such as Apple, Meta, Signal to provide a &amp;ldquo;backdoor&amp;rdquo; into the end to end encryption of messages that would allow the government to snoop on messages sent and received by UK citizens was amended.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a watering down that amounts to the government conceeding defeat they changed the requirement to only apply when it became &amp;ldquo;technically possible&amp;rdquo; for messaging providers to achieve it (there is no way this will ever happen&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t think this should come as a great surprise to anyone really, especially as Apple, Meta and Signal had all written to the government informing them that if the bill went ahead as planned they would remove their services from UK citizens. That would be a great vote winner for the Conservatives in the run up to the next general election now wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it ?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>An Alternative Approach to Preventing Ransomware ?</title><link>https://ukmac.net/p/an-alternative-approach-to-preventing-ransomware/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ukmac.net/p/an-alternative-approach-to-preventing-ransomware/</guid><description>&lt;p>The rise in the prevelance of
&lt;a class="link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ransomware" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Ransomware&lt;/a> hasn&amp;rsquo;t really impacted on Mac Users as it has with the Windows community so far&amp;hellip;
Of course the Mac has benefited from a secure design and being a smaller (relatively) target over the years, but with the growth in use of OS X and the maturity of the tools used by unscrupulous elements this security by obscurity can no longer be guaranteed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When the official downloadable version of the popular BitTorrent client,
&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.transmissionbt.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Transmission&lt;/a>, was infected with a Ransomware client (
&lt;a class="link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KeRanger" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>KeRanger&lt;/a>) in March year it seemed that the reality had come home to roost. The fact is Ransomware poses one of the biggest risks to everyones personal data so it is exciting to hear of a company who are trying to tackle the issue with a form of early detection and blocking for this type of computer virus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="https://objective-see.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Objective-see&lt;/a> is a company created by Patrick Wardle to publish security tools to protect Mac users and one of his products recently released,
&lt;a class="link" href="https://objective-see.com/products/ransomwhere.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>RansomWhere?&lt;/a>, aims to mitigate the impact of a Ransomware infection. It does this by monitoring for activity that looks like Ransomware, notably the rapid modification of multiple files. When it detects suspicious access it identifies and stops the process responsible and prompts the user to warn them that there is a potential ongoing infection. It then offers the option of killing the process or if the alert is a false positive triggered by some known bulk update process for example, to ignore it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This approach is not infallible and of course there may still be a small number of files encrypted before it detects what is going on but if it prevents hundreds or thousands of documents from being irretrievably encrypted (without handing over cash to the Ransomware creators) it is certainly better than nothing, especially when you consider that this is not a pay monthly service or even a pay-for app but is in fact free to download. It should be noted that this is not a fully developed solution and is more of a working proof of concept so you may chose to wait for future more stable version arrives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Patrick&amp;rsquo;s site goes into quite a bit of detail which might put off less technical users and I wonder if this program works well whether it should be launched in a more user friendly package ? It&amp;rsquo;s great to know the detail behind a solution such as this but most users are not that interested, they just need to know what it does and how to install. The low level information can be presented in technical specification page or a blog post. Speaking of which Patrick has a really interesting article on his site titled
&lt;a class="link" href="https://objective-see.com/blog/blog_0x0F.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>&amp;lsquo;Towards Generic Ransomware Detection?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a> that is worth a read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have bookmarked
&lt;a class="link" href="https://objective-see.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Objective-see&lt;/a> and will be watching this project with interest.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hackers find way of breaking out of Apple's sand box ( OS X and iOS )</title><link>https://ukmac.net/p/hackers-find-way-of-breaking-out-of-apples-sand-box-os-x-and-ios/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ukmac.net/p/hackers-find-way-of-breaking-out-of-apples-sand-box-os-x-and-ios/</guid><description>&lt;p>Just this afternoon I was involved in a discussion about how hackers exploit the most difficult to find holes in operating systems, networks and hardware to gain a way in or in some cases out of the protections wrapped around our technology by the people who developed them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These protections are increasingly complex and sophisticated but as
&lt;a class="link" href="http://arstechnica.com/security/2015/06/serious-os-x-and-ios-flaws-let-hackers-steal-keychain-1password-contents/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>this article from Ars Technica&lt;/a> shows the bad guys ( or good guys if they are doing this to expose weaknesses to the vendors rather than using for personal gain ) continue to find ways around and through the barriers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apple have long claimed that their operating systems and software are best in class as far as security is concerned, but as we all know these sort of claims are only going to encourage hackers to prove them wrong, more so over recent years as Apples market share has grown.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hopefully steps are already in place to fix this latest vulnerability.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>