<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hints and Tips on UKmac.net - Apple news, tech views</title><link>/tags/hints-and-tips/</link><description>Recent content in Hints and Tips on UKmac.net - Apple news, tech views</description><generator>Hugo - gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/hints-and-tips/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Resetting Apple’s Magic Keyboard and Magic Trackpad</title><link>/p/resetting-apples-magic-keyboard-and-magic-trackpad/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/p/resetting-apples-magic-keyboard-and-magic-trackpad/</guid><description>&lt;img src="/p/resetting-apples-magic-keyboard-and-magic-trackpad/magickeyboard.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Resetting Apple’s Magic Keyboard and Magic Trackpad" />&lt;p>My Magic Keyboard and Magic Trackpad have been gathering dust in the office recently after I changed from using my MacBook in clamshell mode connected to an external monitor to using in front of the monitor, so I decided to setup them up on my iPad Mini. Trouble is they were paired to my MacBook so didn’t show up in Bluetooth settings on the iPad to pair them and I couldn’t remember how to reset them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The solution for this was quite easy. Just power each device on and off five times, then go to the Bluetooth settings on the iPad and they appear ready for pairing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Managing Trackpad on MacOS when using external mouse</title><link>/p/managing-trackpad-on-macos-when-using-external-mouse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/p/managing-trackpad-on-macos-when-using-external-mouse/</guid><description>&lt;p>Following my desk space re-organisation this weekend I am back to using my MacBook keyboard again for the first time in quite a while. Having worked predominantly with an external mouse and keyboard with my MacBook in clamshell mode in a vertical stand I decided I would like to disable the MacBook trackpad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Simple you would think? Apple do kindly offer a setting in the Mouse &amp;amp; Trackpad Accessibility preferences to do this very thing, however after switching on the option I found my trackpad was still fully operation even with my Logitech MX Master connected. It appears that Bluetooth mice don&amp;rsquo;t register as a mouse being present?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/p/managing-trackpad-on-macos-when-using-external-mouse/mouseoptions.png"
width="827"
height="737"
srcset="/p/managing-trackpad-on-macos-when-using-external-mouse/mouseoptions_hua1225e4738ad67d9b4978907758a8b7f_150480_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, /p/managing-trackpad-on-macos-when-using-external-mouse/mouseoptions_hua1225e4738ad67d9b4978907758a8b7f_150480_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Disabling trackpad when mouse present"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="112"
data-flex-basis="269px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The fix I discovered was to use another Accessibility preference known as Mouse Keys, a legacy service designed to allow cursor control using the keyboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Firstly enable Mouse Keys by switching on the slider in the Pointer Control options, then click on the i next to the slider to reveal the additional preferences dialog below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/p/managing-trackpad-on-macos-when-using-external-mouse/mousekeys.png"
width="827"
height="737"
srcset="/p/managing-trackpad-on-macos-when-using-external-mouse/mousekeys_hub949461989da0550f88f97246b9377c3_165990_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, /p/managing-trackpad-on-macos-when-using-external-mouse/mousekeys_hub949461989da0550f88f97246b9377c3_165990_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Enable mouse keys"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="112"
data-flex-basis="269px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Switch on the two sliders to disable the trackpad when Mouse Keys is on and also enable the option to quickly enable/disable Mouse Keys by pressing the Option key 5 times. You should find that the trackpad is now correctly disabled. To enable the trackpad again just turn off Mouse Keys by tapping Option key 5 times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Job done.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blurred app</title><link>/p/blurred-app/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/p/blurred-app/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/dwarvesf/blurred" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>GitHub - dwarvesf/blurred: A macOS utility that helps reduce distraction by dimming your inactive noise&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are a number of apps in the store that will blur the background windows that aren&amp;rsquo;t in focus as Blurred does. Unlike Blurred most of them are paid for apps. Blurred is free and does its job well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Daily Post - 2/7/2021</title><link>/p/daily-post-2/7/2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/p/daily-post-2/7/2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the things I lost the ability to do as I got older is concentrating/working while listening to certain types of music. I find ambient/electronic is best to listen to whilst working and &lt;a class="link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Klaus_Schulze" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Klaus Schulze&lt;/a> is one of my regular favourites.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week I managed to get hold of a copy of his &lt;a class="link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Ultimate_Edition" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Ultimate Edition&lt;/a> 50 CD box set in FLAC format that I needed to convert to import into Apple Music for playback. Today I came across a nice conversion tool &lt;a class="link" href="https://tmkk.undo.jp/xld/index_e.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>XLD&lt;/a> that I have used to split the single .flac files into seperate Apple Lossless files. If you have flac files with accompanying .cue files XLD will open the cue file and transcode the source file into seperate files quickly and easily. Its a pretty basic application (when you launch it there isn&amp;rsquo;t even a gui interface displayed, just a set of menu options on the menu bar) but is still updated and the latest version even has native Apple Silicon support. There is also a command line version of the app for those who prefer to work in a terminal window.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="daily-links">Daily Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Link&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a class="link" href="https://tmkk.undo.jp/xld/index_e.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>XLD&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>X Lossless Decoder (XLD) is a simple tool for Macs to decode/convert/play lossless audio files. GUI and CLI tool&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a class="link" href="https://readme.so/editor" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>readme.so&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Readme.so is a very simple web site for creating readme.md files quickly and easily. A generic version of this site with user definable blocks would be a great way of creating standard template documents of all sorts.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a class="link" href="https://pandoc.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>pandoc&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Want to convert a markup file to a different format ? Pandoc is your tool&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Moving to Signal</title><link>/p/moving-to-signal/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/p/moving-to-signal/</guid><description>&lt;p>So you make the decision to abandon Whatsapp and want to move to &lt;a class="link" href="https://signal.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Signal&lt;/a>, but how do you convince family and friends (who perhaps aren&amp;rsquo;t as concerned about Facebooks control of the Internet as you) to move with you ?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyone have any convincing arguments that they have made to encourage their friends ?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hidden Bar - menu bar management for macOS</title><link>/p/hidden-bar-menu-bar-management-for-macos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/p/hidden-bar-menu-bar-management-for-macos/</guid><description>&lt;p>Mac menu bar utiities are great for quick access to apps that perform simple tasks and that don&amp;rsquo;t need to sit in the dock or occupy space on your desktop however they do tend to proliferate and before you know it the list of little icons at the top right of your menu bar can get out of control.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are a couple of utilities that aim to help with this. &lt;a class="link" href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/hidden-bar/id1452453066?mt=12" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Hidden Bar&lt;/a> is a simple and free to download app that allows you to quickly hide menu bar icons that you don&amp;rsquo;t want on the screen all the time but still want access to. &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.macbartender.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Bartender&lt;/a> is a pay-for app (currently $15) that goes quite a bit further in features but for my money (ahem) the free Hidden Bar app hits the spot. Worth a look.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>