<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Games on UKmac.net - Apple news, tech views</title><link>https://ukmac.net/categories/games/</link><description>Recent content in Games on UKmac.net - Apple news, tech views</description><generator>Hugo - gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ukmac.net/categories/games/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Game of the day - 2 Cars</title><link>https://ukmac.net/p/game-of-the-day-2-cars/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ukmac.net/p/game-of-the-day-2-cars/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of my favourite quick-fix games at the moment is &lt;a class="link" href="https://geo.itunes.apple.com/gb/app/2-cars/id936839198?mt=8&amp;amp;at=1000lbQg" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>2 Cars from Ketchapp&lt;/a>. It is a very simple top to bottom scroller where the objective is to steer your &lt;strong>2 Cars&lt;/strong> around the oncoming square blocks whilst at the same time intercepting the round blocks. Any collision with a square block ends the game. Any round block missed also ends the game. Each car can drive in one of two lanes and the only control is to tap the screen on the right to move the right hand car to the alternate lane and the screen on the left to move the left hand car.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sounds simple doesn&amp;rsquo;t it ? Well give it a try and see how far you get, I can pretty much guarantee it will take you quite a few goes before you progress to double digit scores and after that progression is likely to be slow as the speed of the oncoming blocks increases pretty quickly once you get into the 40-50 score bracket.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An enjoyable game for passing a few minutes !&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Infinite Loop - Lovely Relaxing Game for iOS</title><link>https://ukmac.net/p/infinite-loop-lovely-relaxing-game-for-ios/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ukmac.net/p/infinite-loop-lovely-relaxing-game-for-ios/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="http://loopgame.co" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Infinite Loop&lt;/a> is my latest go to iPhone game for instant gratification or the gamers equivalent of meditation. Jonas Lekevicious has created a beautiful puzzle game that requires no instructions and is suitable for young and old. Whats more he has created an
&lt;a class="link" href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/infinite-loop/id977028266?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>iPhone&lt;/a> and
&lt;a class="link" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.balysv.loop" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Android&lt;/a> version so everyone can play.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Grab it now its free to play.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>