<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Zwift on UKmac.net - Apple news, tech views</title><link>https://ukmac.net/categories/zwift/</link><description>Recent content in Zwift on UKmac.net - Apple news, tech views</description><generator>Hugo - gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ukmac.net/categories/zwift/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A short break from work..</title><link>https://ukmac.net/p/a-short-break-from-work../</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ukmac.net/p/a-short-break-from-work../</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://ukmac.net/p/a-short-break-from-work../2023-10-30-zwift.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A short break from work.." />&lt;p>I am taking a few days leave for half term this week so today was busy busy busy&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This morning started with a quick ride on stage 5 of Tour of Watopia (Canopies and Coastlines). This route started with the Titans Grove KOM reverse before taking in the new Watopia coastal road and finally ending at Sasquatch Sprint all in just over 28km and about 245m of climbing. A nice route made nicer by having the garage door open to let some Autumn sunshine in.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- html codes here-->
&lt;div class="strava-embed-placeholder" data-embed-type="activity" data-embed-id="10129684908">&lt;/div>&lt;script src="https://strava-embeds.com/embed.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;p>Ride out of the way and onto chores, hopefully the last grass cut of the year followed by cleaning the roof panels from the gazebo ready to be stored away for the winter. Later in the afternoon when the clouds opened with a torrential downpour I was pretty glad I chose the morning to get these jobs sorted.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The afternoon was then spent in my office, sorting out shelving, listening to music and organising cabling ( a favourite pastime of mine ) on my new standing desk. Tomorrow I have some LED light strips coming from Amazon that I am going to use to brighten the office space a bit so part of Tuesday is already planned&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="daily-links">Daily Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Link&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a class="link" href="https://sergii.tatarenkov.name/keyclu/support/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Keyclu&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Simple and handy overview of applications shortcuts. Press Command key twice and hold to display the keyboard shortcuts available for the current application.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a class="link" href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/app/dropzone-4/id1485052491?mt=12" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Dropzone 4&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>A menu bar utility to make copy/paste between apps easier. Great if you use Stage Manager&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item></channel></rss>