<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Strava on UKmac.net - Apple news, tech views</title><link>/tags/strava/</link><description>Recent content in Strava on UKmac.net - Apple news, tech views</description><generator>Hugo - gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/strava/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Morning Run (4 miles) - Scary Fast</title><link>/p/morning-run-4-miles-scary-fast/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/p/morning-run-4-miles-scary-fast/</guid><description>&lt;img src="/p/morning-run-4-miles-scary-fast/scary-fast.png" alt="Featured image of post Morning Run (4 miles) - Scary Fast" />&lt;h2 id="morning-run">Morning Run&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>First longish run for a long time this morning. Dropped Vel&amp;rsquo;s car at the garage for a service then run home. Felt pretty slow but looking at the total time and distance it actually wasn&amp;rsquo;t too bad. I enjoy running when I am doing it regularly and I can get to a decent pace without feeling like my lungs are going to burst but to get to that usually means a prolonged period of regular runs and at the moment I am not getting out often enough. Oddly running is something I tend to find I do more of in the winter, I find running in the hot weather uncomfortable and would much rather be cycling through the lanes for exercise in the Summer. The big benefit of running though is that 30-45 mins gets me the same benefit as a much longer day in the saddle so fitting into the family life schedule is generally easier.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- html codes here-->
&lt;div class="strava-embed-placeholder" data-embed-type="activity" data-embed-id="10134903273">&lt;/div>&lt;script src="https://strava-embeds.com/embed.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;h2 id="scary-fast">Scary Fast&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As predicted the Halloween Apple Event happened last night was all about the M3 processor laucnch in new versions of the MacBook Pro. The M3 is another incremental improvement over the previous generations Apple Silicon so it was interesting that most of the performance comparisons that Apple made during the event were between the M1 and M3 processors rather than between M2 and M3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I suppose the point of making this comparison is to encourage early Apple Silicon adopters who are on M1 machines to upgrade even though for most users those M1 based Macs are still going to be fine for almost all uses. This is also why the event repeatedly referred to high end/power users. Its very clear the M3 Pro MacBooks are targetted to heavy users (video, simulation, audio production etc). This will be a challenge for Apple moving forward. Whilst two year iPhone upgrades cycles are commonplace for many users MacBooks and Macs tend to be on longer upgrade cycles and the new Apple Silicon Macs are SO fast and powerful this cycle will potentially be able to stretch even longer. I know for me the ugrade of my current M1 MacBook Pro is likely to be some time away.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="daily-links">Daily Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Link&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a class="link" href="https://bunchapp.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Bunch&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Bunch is another great tool from &lt;a class="link" href="https://brettterpstra.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Brett Terpstra&lt;/a> that uses a plain text config file to define bunches of apps that can be lauched together from a simple menu. Think of the contexts of how you use your Mac (work, home, play) and the common apps that you use in each context, Bunch makes launching and closing apps to get you from one context to another simple.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>A short break from work..</title><link>/p/a-short-break-from-work../</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/p/a-short-break-from-work../</guid><description>&lt;img src="/p/a-short-break-from-work../2023-10-30-zwift.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A short break from work.." />&lt;p>I am taking a few days leave for half term this week so today was busy busy busy&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This morning started with a quick ride on stage 5 of Tour of Watopia (Canopies and Coastlines). This route started with the Titans Grove KOM reverse before taking in the new Watopia coastal road and finally ending at Sasquatch Sprint all in just over 28km and about 245m of climbing. A nice route made nicer by having the garage door open to let some Autumn sunshine in.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- html codes here-->
&lt;div class="strava-embed-placeholder" data-embed-type="activity" data-embed-id="10129684908">&lt;/div>&lt;script src="https://strava-embeds.com/embed.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;p>Ride out of the way and onto chores, hopefully the last grass cut of the year followed by cleaning the roof panels from the gazebo ready to be stored away for the winter. Later in the afternoon when the clouds opened with a torrential downpour I was pretty glad I chose the morning to get these jobs sorted.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The afternoon was then spent in my office, sorting out shelving, listening to music and organising cabling ( a favourite pastime of mine ) on my new standing desk. Tomorrow I have some LED light strips coming from Amazon that I am going to use to brighten the office space a bit so part of Tuesday is already planned&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="daily-links">Daily Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Link&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a class="link" href="https://sergii.tatarenkov.name/keyclu/support/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Keyclu&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Simple and handy overview of applications shortcuts. Press Command key twice and hold to display the keyboard shortcuts available for the current application.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a class="link" href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/app/dropzone-4/id1485052491?mt=12" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Dropzone 4&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>A menu bar utility to make copy/paste between apps easier. Great if you use Stage Manager&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>What a difference a week makes</title><link>/p/what-a-difference-a-week-makes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/p/what-a-difference-a-week-makes/</guid><description>&lt;img src="/p/what-a-difference-a-week-makes/wrekin-from-edgmond.jpg" alt="Featured image of post What a difference a week makes" />&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="https://ukmac.net/p/a-lesson-in-how-not-to-ride-in-the-rain/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Last weeks ride&lt;/a> couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been more different from todays. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure I would get time to go out this afternoon but when the opportunity of a quick hour circuit raised its head I didn&amp;rsquo;t wait for it to pass by.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know I am really lucky to be near enough to quiet country lanes that I dont need to plan ahead to get my bike in the car and drive to a starting point and the &lt;a class="link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/North_Shropshire_%28UK_Parliament_constituency%29" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>North Shropshire&lt;/a> countryside has some really enjoyable cycling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My route today was only 40K but this was enough enough to blow the cobwebs away and get me ready for a week at the home office.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- html codes here-->
&lt;div class="strava-embed-placeholder" data-embed-type="activity" data-embed-id="9775408693">&lt;/div>&lt;script src="https://strava-embeds.com/embed.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;h2 id="gallery">Gallery&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/p/what-a-difference-a-week-makes/me.jpg"
width="480"
height="640"
srcset="/p/what-a-difference-a-week-makes/me_hu2c6c0833fcc1a45fd0da19b45234341b_108166_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, /p/what-a-difference-a-week-makes/me_hu2c6c0833fcc1a45fd0da19b45234341b_108166_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Enjoying the sun"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="75"
data-flex-basis="180px"
> &lt;img src="/p/what-a-difference-a-week-makes/roadsign.jpg"
width="640"
height="480"
srcset="/p/what-a-difference-a-week-makes/roadsign_hu444b214d355c0838f9f4986c6f9f8e92_123784_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, /p/what-a-difference-a-week-makes/roadsign_hu444b214d355c0838f9f4986c6f9f8e92_123784_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Road sign"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
> &lt;img src="/p/what-a-difference-a-week-makes/wrekin-from-edgmond.jpg"
width="640"
height="480"
srcset="/p/what-a-difference-a-week-makes/wrekin-from-edgmond_hua3face1d1ce06f2465e839e25cab6f00_121766_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, /p/what-a-difference-a-week-makes/wrekin-from-edgmond_hua3face1d1ce06f2465e839e25cab6f00_121766_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Wrekin from Edgmond"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
> &lt;img src="/p/what-a-difference-a-week-makes/wrekin-view.jpg"
width="640"
height="480"
srcset="/p/what-a-difference-a-week-makes/wrekin-view_hudd468150c7b4fb6a3c9608435d80f283_114547_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, /p/what-a-difference-a-week-makes/wrekin-view_hudd468150c7b4fb6a3c9608435d80f283_114547_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Wrekin from Preston on the Weald Moors"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A lesson in how not to ride in the rain</title><link>/p/a-lesson-in-how-not-to-ride-in-the-rain/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/p/a-lesson-in-how-not-to-ride-in-the-rain/</guid><description>&lt;img src="/p/a-lesson-in-how-not-to-ride-in-the-rain/strava.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A lesson in how not to ride in the rain" />&lt;h2 id="a-wet-ride">A wet ride&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I should have gone with my gut this afternoon when I was planning a short ride. Just before I set off the clouds opened and it poured down. I had just checked on my weather app and it did say no rain so I decided it was just a short downpour and I should go for it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first 10 minutes were ok but by the time I reached &lt;a class="link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kynnersley" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Kynnersley&lt;/a> it was raining again and slowly got heavier. I ploughed on as I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been out on the roads for a while and wanted to do at least 30k. By the time I reached the turn for Ollerton/Childs Ercall I was well and truly soaked and so decided to take the corner off the ride and not go to Ollerton and to head straight to [Childs Ercall(https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Child%27s_Ercall)] instead. This turned out to be the wrong choice. As I took the right hand turn to Childs Ercall I felt the back wheel go and before I knew where I was I was on my side on the edge of the road ! Not what I had planned.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fortunately I was largely unhurt apart from my right arm having a nice bit of road rash. Thankfully it is a quiet country lane and there were no cars around.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/p/a-lesson-in-how-not-to-ride-in-the-rain/roadrash.jpg"
width="480"
height="640"
srcset="/p/a-lesson-in-how-not-to-ride-in-the-rain/roadrash_hu213aa2599efca4dee3f8c057f165d464_110325_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, /p/a-lesson-in-how-not-to-ride-in-the-rain/roadrash_hu213aa2599efca4dee3f8c057f165d464_110325_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Road Rash"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="75"
data-flex-basis="180px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After straightening my handlebars and brushing myself down I continued on with the rest of the wet ride home. This was my first spill on a bike for many years but it didn&amp;rsquo;t make it feel any less embarrassing that I had fallen off.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I suspect tonight I will feel the impact of this fall as the bruising comes through but at least I am in one piece and ready to ride again, albeit I will probably take it a little more gingerley on the corners when the roads are wet next time.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- html codes here-->
&lt;div class="strava-embed-placeholder" data-embed-type="activity" data-embed-id="9723918334">&lt;/div>&lt;script src="https://strava-embeds.com/embed.js">&lt;/script></description></item></channel></rss>